[Music]
thank you
today I'm gathering arnica it is a
healing flower and grows wild in the
forest of my home
this year I found a lot of it in an area
that succumbed to fires not long ago and
it reminds me that no matter how bad
things get even watching an entire
Forest burn down if you wait long enough
and have faith life will Begin Again
[Music]
thank you
foreign
[Music]
there are so many bees and birds
everywhere it is such a chorus of noise
so you may not be able to hear me at all
but I just wanted to share this moment
with you because this field of arnica is
so abundant it makes me happier just to
be here I don't have to do anything but
just be and the vibrancy of the color
just puts me in a better mood it
occurred to me that I think that is one
of the most meaningful and fulfilling
Parts about simple living and it is
about repetition and embracing The
rhythms of the seasons and every late
spring I gather arnica and I do
something with it just show you that I I
think that if there's one thing I
connect to the true Joy of simple living
it is embracing those cycles of Nature
and those seasons and the beauty of
Simplicity and repetition
so I'm gonna collect some arnica again I
hope you as well can enjoy the cyclical
nature of the seasons in your own life
and enjoy those daily rhythms and
predictable practices
all right let's get some flowers buddy
[Music]
as many of you know I had a rather
alternative upbringing and grew up
mostly without using social media it was
only now as an adult that I use it
regularly I love to keep track of other
artists and Book Lovers it makes my life
better especially as I live in a small
rural community and don't always find
people locally who share my interests
the online space can be wonderful but
also sometimes rather cynical with
normalized doom scrolling and the
constant critique of others as seemingly
entertainment
this got me thinking about how easy it
is to surround yourself with negative
thoughts and perspectives on The Daily
in our real lives and how this practice
is deeply unhealthy in my personal case
I had certain life experiences myself
that left me quite distressful and
negative
I held on to pent up anger unsure what
to do with it and therefore projected it
onto others the society at large and had
a quite dismal Outlook in regards to the
Future
later in this video I will go into this
more and you may be surprised
[Music]
thank you
I think my negativity was one of the
reasons I was attracted to simple slow
living because the era of mindful
quietness I entered changed things for
me it isn't the answer for everyone
we're all different but it worked for me
and made me realize that the cynical and
Jada daily mindset only contributed to a
feeling of burnout and left me
uninspired to be a force for good and do
something meaningful with my life
oh
my God
[Music]
foreign
no doubt it is healthy for us to share
our feelings when we feel frustrated or
despairing and talk about injustices and
individuals making poor decisions I do
this as well but I can't bring myself to
express them by looking down on others
and the world in general I like to use
that energy instead to do acts of
kindness even if it's in small ways I
attempt to find Joy despite the darkness
with hope in the power of goodness and
that there's a whole lot of goodness in
the world as well as ugliness seeing
both does not make the bad any less real
but it reminds us that there are many
who are fighting for Change and
spreading love along the way and their
efforts are valid and beautiful and
should make the news more often in my
personal opinion maybe I'm wrong and my
perspective seems silly to you but I do
know that I'd much rather spend my life
trying to make the world a better place
and choose friendships with people who
believe it's possible then giving up
before I even try
foreign
on this painting for several days now
and I was taking inspiration from all
the wild herbs and Edibles that are
either medicinal or that you can consume
them there are so many incredible
flowers and herbs in this area and so I
wanted to put them together in one
entire art piece so far I have put veg
mint Purple Sage blueberry Fireweed
tansy Burdock chicory yarrow rosemary
thyme wild strawberry violets dandelions
and several others it is certainly
featuring a lot of very special herbs
and flowers I think one of my favorites
is chicory because I've grown it before
and I just really love the color anyway
you can see where my creativity has led
me this week it has definitely been
inspired by all the beautiful flowers My
Hope Is by the time this video is up
this will be a new original art piece in
my Etsy shop I hope I also hope to be
selling some original paintings and some
large prints and posters so hopefully
all that will be coming soon as you can
see I'm spending a lot of time on my
porch and I know that that does mean
that the audio is not quite as crisp as
it usually is indoors however I was
hoping that you would appreciate
enjoying the springtime with me and all
the nature sounds I was listening to
this podcast that was interviewing an
actor who many of you probably know
Rayne Wilson and he was talking about
his experience with feeling quite
cynical and negative at certain points
in his life and how he worked through
some of those emotions and there was one
point in the podcast where I'm just
gonna have to leave a link down to it
below because what he says it just rang
so true for me he was warned by a wise
man not to be cynical because if he gave
in to Too Much negativity and felt like
he didn't have a sense of agency in his
life and in the world he would never
help make the world a better place I
know I had some experiences in my life
that made it very hard for me to see
things through a positive Viewpoint for
many many years I believe I had a lot of
anger pent up in myself and I didn't
really know what to do with that anger
and so I would just project it onto
others and just feeling quite dismal it
is interesting though to look back at my
younger self someone who is quite
cynical someone who was in college
studying a lot of philosophy reading a
lot of books with very upsetting themes
and it was hard not to feel that way but
I have to admit I created a bit of a
habit of that overwhelming daily
negativity and I surrounded myself with
people that kind of shared that
perspective on life but I will be
brutally honest with you and I at one
point I felt a lot of shame in admitting
this but I think I liked being cynical
and negative I think it gave me this
very immature very immature so sense of
superiority over others that I could
just judge people on the smallest things
without taking any substantial amount of
time for self-reflection and realizing
that my own beliefs and mindsets could
be quite narrow-minded and quite
judgmental and stubborn in my ways and I
think it's good to have convictions and
go good to have Noble convictions it's
important but for me my practice of
conviction was not being truly open to
listen and understand other viewpoints
and even when I disagreed I didn't try
to practice compassion and kindness and
I didn't try to reflect on my own more
narrow-minded perspectives and I
appreciate that that is very different
now in my life and I am a lot more
willing to see others perspectives I
don't need to agree with them but I can
much easier understand where they're
coming from and respect them it makes it
a lot easier to love people openly and I
find it it makes it easier to love
myself because if I am kind to others
even when they make mistakes or they
have perspectives I don't agree with I
can be more kind to myself when I
realize my own flaws as you can tell I
am admitting you know a really huge
character flaw I had years ago and that
was something that I was ashamed of for
so long after I kind of realized that it
was not serving me in any positive way
however I am sharing it because
obviously I am not perfect I am far from
it and I hope that it can inspire all of
you to be kinder to yourselves as well I
think when we choose humility true
humility you know isn't being hard on
yourself it's accepting that these
things happen and this is the way you
grow and you evolve we have some very
very very exciting new news in the
cottage fairy household we have a new
friend in our lives her name is Luna and
she is so soft she is as soft as a piece
of high quality velvet and she is so
sweet and certainly the gentlest bunny
I've ever had I was having a few very
difficult days and she helped me through
it and she is just a little angel so I'm
very excited to introduce her to all of
you she is a sweetheart I'm sending all
of you my love thank you so much for
spending this beautiful day with me and
I appreciate all the support of my work
as an artist it makes this channel
happen and I couldn't do it without that
so thank you so much again I'm sending
you a well wishes for a wonderful week
and I will see you very soon
[Music]